<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-12-04T01:34:24+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Learning and Sharing</title><subtitle>An amazing website about learning and sharing.</subtitle><author><name>sdrsiddiqui</name></author><entry><title type="html">How to make a blog like this?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/How-to-make-a-blog-like-this/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to make a blog like this?" /><published>2018-11-29T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-11-29T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/How%20to%20make%20a%20blog%20like%20this</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/How-to-make-a-blog-like-this/">&lt;p&gt;Whenever we hear about blogs we think more often about WordPress or BlogSpot blogs. &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; is more popular once right now. It is an open source online website creation tool, which was written in PHP and MySQL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of people complain about their WordPress blog getting infected with malware or hacked, or being slow etc. Let us learn about Jekyll and how it overcomes the problems mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introducing-jekyll&quot;&gt;Introducing Jekyll&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll transforms plain text into static websites. It is a simple static site generator, and takes a source file (written in markup language) for creating a static website.
It supports all kinds of file formats and is good for quickly creating a blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In 2009, Jekyll was written in Ruby, by &lt;a href=&quot;http://tom.preston-werner.com/&quot;&gt;Tom Preston-Werner&lt;/a&gt;, GitHub’s co-founder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though it needs some technical background and a good knowledge of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.markdownguide.org/getting-started&quot;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://shopify.github.io/liquid/&quot;&gt;Liquid&lt;/a&gt; templating language, which is easy to learn if you have some basics of HTML. Ever since it is getting popular and glimpse of Jekyll popularity can be seen on &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/showcase/&quot;&gt;Showcase&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll/wiki/sites&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this blog, I preferred &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; because of the following reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance:&lt;/strong&gt; Extremely fast as web server only returns static files.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secure:&lt;/strong&gt; There are only static files which means content is not produced dynamically, so there is no chance for it to get exploited or hacked. Until someone hacked the server.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Less costly:&lt;/strong&gt; It requires less resources which reduces its operative cost.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy to learn:&lt;/strong&gt; If you know HTML, CSS and JavaScript then only learning a new templating language called &lt;a href=&quot;https://shopify.github.io/liquid/&quot;&gt;Liquid&lt;/a&gt; will suffice.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low maintenance:&lt;/strong&gt; With first-class support for Markdown, and the Liquid templating language, making a blog is as easy as running two commands. It takes less then five minutes for setting up Jekyll and the maintaining cost is minimum.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big community:&lt;/strong&gt; Jekyll has big active community and a team of Core maintainers which is working hard to maintain it. They have documented Jekyll very well.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Learning Experience:&lt;/strong&gt; Blogging is a the best way to learn and share about new technologies. We learn more by teaching others and while getting your hands dirty with real world problems.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tldr-procedure-for-creating-a-blog-on-jekyll-like-this-one&quot;&gt;TL;DR Procedure for creating a blog on Jekyll like this one:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&quot;https://rubyinstaller.org/&quot;&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/installation/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/ruby-101/#bundler&quot;&gt;bundler gems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mmistakes/minimal-mistakes&quot;&gt;theme&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modify the &lt;strong&gt;GEMFILE&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modify &lt;strong&gt;_config.yml&lt;/strong&gt; file.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run the server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is written in Ruby so we have to install Ruby as well and it is one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/ruby-101/#gems&quot;&gt;Ruby Gem&lt;/a&gt;.
This &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/5233924/what-is-a-ruby-gem&quot;&gt;stackoverflow  answer on Gem&lt;/a&gt; explains very well about Gem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;RubyGems is a package manager for the Ruby programming language that provides a standard format for distributing Ruby programs and libraries (in a self-contained format called a “gem”), a tool designed to easily manage the installation of gems, and a server for distributing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can find the detail installation process on the Jekyll website &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/installation/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; but nevertheless we can find the procedure below as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I used Windows(O.S) I will follow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can download the repository by two ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.
  a. Click on the link  and  download the repository. Save the file in the desired folder and unzip it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b. Open Git bash and clone the repository like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to install Ruby for Jekyll. If you don’t have Ruby installed on your pc then download from here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go inside the folder. Find the Gemfile and modify it like this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;source 'https://rubygems.org'
gem &quot;minimal-mistakes-jekyll&quot;
gem 'jekyll-include-cache'
gem 'jekyll-archives'
&lt;/code&gt;
  Save the file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Open the file __config.yml&lt;br /&gt;
search for “plugins” (line - 225) and add the following lines
 -jekyll-include-cache
 -jekyll-archives&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;search for jekyll-archives and uncomment the lines from 262 till 270&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Open the bash&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ATOM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;markdown-preview&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;REFERENCES&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://jekyllrb.com/&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll/wiki/sites&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://jekyllrb.com/showcase/&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://rubyinstaller.org/&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://github.com/adam-p/markdown-here/wiki/Markdown-Here-Cheatsheet#emphasis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/ruby-101/#gems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>sdrsiddiqui</name></author><category term="Jekyll" /><category term="Liquid" /><summary type="html">Whenever we hear about blogs we think more often about WordPress or BlogSpot blogs. WordPress is more popular once right now. It is an open source online website creation tool, which was written in PHP and MySQL.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Atom</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/post/Atom-eidtor/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Atom" /><published>2018-11-29T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-11-29T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/post/Atom-eidtor</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/post/Atom-eidtor/">&lt;p&gt;Atom&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Atom is a very powerful editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to the official webpage of Atom(https://atom.io) and download the Atom for 64 bit installer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install the Atom. Wait until Atom is installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally to open Atom, we browse to the program and click on the Atom icon which opens in a random directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it cool if we can open the Atom in any directory without changing the directory all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this we have to some changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open Atom&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Click on File &amp;gt; Settings and Click “System” tab.
 Check the second and third options.
   Show in file context menus
   Show in folder context menus&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Close Atom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right click and you will see “open with Atom”.
Now you can open the Atom anywhere you want to open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make Atom ready for Python&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;File &amp;gt; Settings &amp;gt; Install
then search “script” and install it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it will let the python file to run from the Atom.
Write a code in python and then use keyboard shortcuts Ctrl + shift + b for windows and unix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are other ways also. Where we can integrate command line in ATOM so that we don’t need other windows for command line.
  File&amp;gt; Settings&amp;gt;Install
  “platform-ide-terminal”
On the left side there will be a “plus” sign. click on it and a new command line window will appear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you press Ctrl+T or Ctrl+P, the Fuzzy Finder will pop up. This will let you quickly search for any file in your project by typing parts of the path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;File&amp;gt;Settings&amp;gt;Install another package
  a. “autocomplete-python”.
  This will make your life more easy as python developer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b. “python-autopep8”
  this format the python code according to the PEP8 guidelines. more information could be find here https://pypi.org/project/autopep8/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  1. to use this we need to install autopep8 by using pip install autopep8 in the bash
  2. Click on the Settings of python-autopep8 and go to the Settings. check the format on Save
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;c. “linter-flake8”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Flake8 is a Python library that wraps PyFlakes, pycodestyle and Ned Batchelder’s McCabe script. It is a great toolkit for checking your code base against coding style (PEP8), programming errors (like “library imported but unused” and “Undefined name”) and to check cyclomatic complexity.
https://simpleisbetterthancomplex.com/packages/2016/08/05/flake8.html

1. To use this plugin flake8 will need to be installed on your system.
  pip install flake8 from the bash
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;d. “Browser Plus”
     Install this. It opens a real browser in ATOM. Which is very handy for debugging and checking the output at the same time.
     ctrl+shift+p(cmd+shift+p) Browser Plus: Open. It opens the home page(maintained in the settings) or http://www.google.com.
     ctrl + shift + P to open the browser window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;e . “file-icons”
  This put a little icon next to each file, which helps us to identify which kind of file it is. File-specific icons in Atom for improved visual grepping.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sdrsiddiqui</name></author><category term="Atom" /><category term="editor" /><summary type="html">Atom</summary></entry></feed>